# **Muhammad Rehman**

# Senior Software Engineer

Email: m.rehmanfullstack@gmail.com

Contact No: +923074625308 Nationality: Pakistani Date of Birth: Oct-1-996

LinkedIn Profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/MuhammadRehmanSSE/

## **OBJECTIVE**

Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience and a proven track record of making significant, specific, and self-direction contributions to challenging and complex projects. Seeking a position to apply exceptional problem-solving ,Creative thinker, a talented individual who has strong communication skills and collaborative skills as part of a team.

## **Professional EXPERIENCE**

Company: Tkxel

Designation: Senior Software engineer | Project Manager

Responsibility:

Website: <a href="https://tkxel.com/">https://tkxel.com/</a>
(Oct 2021 - Still working)

- Scrum Master. Project Sprint Planning. Team Management. Client Communication.
- Fronted Project Design in React.js. Component & Architecture design.
- Server Management Node.is with express framework implementation.
- Tool: (AWS EC2, S3 BUCKET, DOCKER, Jira, VScode, AWS Lambda. MongoDB)

Company: Arhamsoft
Designation: Software engineer | Team Lead
Responsibility:

Website: <a href="https://www.arhamsoft.com/">https://www.arhamsoft.com/</a>
(Apr 2019 - Aug 2021)

- Client Communication.
  - Fronted Project Design in React.js. Component Design.
  - Node js with express framework implementation.
  - Tool: (AWS EC2, Jira, VScode, AWS Lambda. MongoDB AngularJS | NodeJS)

Company: Novatore Solution

Designation: Software engineer

Responsibility:

Website: <a href="https://novatoresols.com/">https://novatoresols.com/</a>
(Aug 2018 - Apr 2019)

- Client Communication.
- Fronted Project Design in React.js..
- Node.js with express framework implementation.
- Tool: (AWS EC2, Jira, VScode, AWS Lambda. MongoDB AngularJS | NodeJS )

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor in Computer Sciences from University of Education Country Pakistan in (2014 to 2018).

**CGPA**: 3.35/4.00

Higher Secondary in Pre-Engineering from Freedom College Country Pakistan in (2011 to 2013).

**Grade: 80%** 

### **SKILLS**

- FrameWork: React.js, Angular.js, Loopback, Node.js, Express.js. (MEAN & MERN STACK)
- Language: JAVASCRIPT, PHP.
- **Databases:** Mongodb, MYSQL, FireBase.
- Server/Deployment: AWS, Digital Oceans, Heroku, Apache, Nginx, LINUX, MAC & Window

## **PROJECTS**

#### Digno

**Description**: The project collects information from different project management and human management software and then digno create user score against all running departments, Projects. It helps the CEO calculate the company processes.

Platform/Tools: React.is, Node.is, express.is, MongoDB, vs code

#### **Lead Generation Project**

**Description**: 100+ Small Projects (Lead generating websites for Facebook and Google Ads).

Platform/Tools: React.js, Node.js, express.js, MongoDB, vsCode, Php

#### **Lead Generation Project**

**Description**: 100+ Small Projects (Lead generating websites for Facebook and Google Ads).

Platform/Tools: React.js, Node.js, express.js, MongoDB, vsCode, Php

#### EsignPanda:

**Description**: Online contracts channel with e-signing and drag n drop template documents builder. Built Using (NodeJS, ReactJS and MongoDB). AWS load balancing, Auto Scaling, S3, and Mongo

Platform/Tools: React.js, Node.js, express.js, MongoDB, vsCode

Link: www.esignpanda.com

#### **EsignRepack**

**Description**: A marketing software to collect leads for call centers (Many kinds of Email, Sms Integration

with Url Shortener many more). Built Using (NodeJS, ReactJS and MongoDB)

Platform/Tools: React.js, Node.js, express.js, MongoDB, vsCode

Link: www.esignrepack.co.uk

#### Flo.ink

**Description**: URL shortening and stats management app, where users can shorten links and review traffic as well as manage using campaigns and channels. Users can purchase packages according to their requirements and can share links on social media.

Platform/Tools: React.js, Node.js, express.js, MongoDB, vsCode

Link: flo.ink